# **Raman Singh**

LinkedIn | GitHub | Leetcode

Email: ramansinghdsat@gmail.com | Mobile: +91 8104771721

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Highly skilled web and app developer with nearly 1 year of experience in React Native, MongoDB, and Typescript. Proficient in frameworks such as React, Android Studio, and ExpressJS, with experience in REST APIs and MVC frameworks.

#### **PROJECTS**

## **Google Docs Clone**

ReactJs, Nodejs, WebSockets, Quill, MongoDB

Source Code

Location: Bangalore, IN

- Implemented live cursor tracking using WebSockets, enhancing real-time visibility for collaborative editing.
- Decreased server load by 30% by employing Redis to store and efficiently retrieve documents, optimizing performance.

### **Placement Management System**

Node.js, Express, JavaScript, Git

Source Code

- Developed a Nodejs backend for a user-friendly Placement Management System, integrating HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and EJS
- Enabled efficient admin management of monitoring placement activities and results
- Implemented dynamic frontend elements using Bootstrap enhancing the user interface.

#### **Scalable Chat Application**

Typescript, Nodejs, Redis

Source Code

- Designed and developed a scalable real-time chat application using Socket.io, Reactjs, Redis on Aiven cloud and Turborepo.
- Utilized React Context hook to manage the states of the messages.
- Implemented Redis PUB/SUB architecture to scale the Websocket servers

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages : JavaScript, TypeScript, GoLang, Java

**Frameworks** : React.js, React Native, Express, Node.js,NestJs

**Libraries** : Tailwind CSS, Redux, React Router

**Databases** : MongoDB, PostgreSQL

**Dev Tools** : Git, Gitlab, Docker, ORM (Prisma)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Application Developer**

Mar 2023 – Aug 2023

Remote

Felesys Technologies

- Implemented a caching system in the backend architecture, resulting in a significant reduction of backend latency by 20%, thereby improving the overall performance and responsiveness of the API.
- Provided data validation rules and resolved inconsistencies in the database models, resulting in streamlined processes and improved data accuracy by 30%.
- Developed and integrated with REST APIs to retrieve and display data efficiently.

## **Application Developer**

Aug 2023 - Oct 2023

Remote

- Developed a event planning application with React Native Router Props Context providers for smooth navigation and data handling
- Boosted application performance and speed by 55% through optimization strategies.
- Developed a robust fronted in React Native that interacts seamlessly with backend API's

## **EDUCATION**

Phurti.in

**Dayanada Sagar Academy of Technology and Management** 

Bengaluru, IN Jan 2021 – May 2024